HUSSAIN AZIZ SAIF

+971 50 1670243 # HUSSAIN.AZIZSAIF@GMAIL.COM # DUBAI, UAE

LINKEDIN # GITHUB # PORTFOLIO

Professional Profile

Senior Computer Engineering student with a passion for technology and problem-solving. Developed programs in C++, C#, Dart, and python and created websites hosted in AWS using React and Django. Has a keen interest in machine learning and is currently working on publishing a research paper on anomalous factory machine sound detection using auto encoder neural networks.

Education

BSc Computer Engineering with minor in Data Science

at American University of Sharjah, UAE. (Expected Graduation: May 2024) **Relevant Courses**: Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Computer Security

Work Experience

Internship - December 2023 to January 2024

Marshall Radio Telemetry Gulf, Dubai, UAE

- Designed a dynamic website using React that displays analytics and user locations on a map.
- Developed APIs in *Django* to efficiently query the database of 4k+ users to generate analytics.

Internship – July 2023 to August 2023

Petrofac, Sharjah, UAE

 Leveraged UI Path to design and implement an automated workflow for extracting invoices from an internal web platform, enhancing operational efficiency by replacing manual processes.

Certifications

- AWS Academy Cloud Foundations Course Amazon, February 2021.
- RedHat System Administration (RH124) RedHat, January 2024.

Honors

- Tau Beta Pi Engineering Honor Society at American University of Sharjah May 2023
- IEEE Eta Kappa Nu Lambda Lambda Chapter at American University of Sharjah May 2022

Skills

- Proficient in Python, JavaScript, C++, C#, Java.
- Familiarity with keras and scikit-learn, pandas.
- Experienced with React, Avalonia UI, Flutter.
- Competent with Django, and ASP.NET.
- Strong oral and technical communication.

GPA: 3.82/4

- Creative and reliable team player.
- Effective time management and organization skills.

Projects

Lumafly – January 2023 – Ongoing (view project)

A fully featured, cross platform desktop app written in C# which currently has 175k+ downloads.

IEEE EV race car project – September 2022 - May 2023. (view project)

Developed the car's dashboard, which displays the car's speed and other information.

Anomalous Sound Detection – September 2023 – Ongoing (view project)

Uses keras to create auto encoder neural networks for anomaly detection in factory machine sounds.
Detected anomalous sounds with 80% precision and recall.